[{"id": "6014c80dfbde8045e48466cd", "question": "Tercel is the name for the male of which animal?", "answer": "Hawk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd2d76a2596a59cbdfbd3b5", "question": "Which famous work did Thomas Paine write?", "answer": "Common Sense", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c395", "question": "What prevents the Earth's atmosphere from drifting into space?", "answer": "Gravity", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c02", "question": "Tony Pastor is credited with popularizing what form of theater in the early 1880s?", "answer": "Vaudeville", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe36b810ada16518afdc03b", "question": "What animal is on the label of \"Shiner Bock\" beer?", "answer": "Big-Horned Sheep", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae55", "question": "Who was the first chancellor of the reunited Germany?", "answer": "Helmut Kohl", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2bb", "question": "What year saw the debut of the TV show \"30 Rock\"?", "answer": "2006", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e5f", "question": "According to the poem, how many spectators saw Mighty Casey strike out?", "answer": "Five thousand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3a4", "question": "Which is the most densely populated country in the world?", "answer": "Monaco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4fc", "question": "Which island is the boot of Italy kicking?", "answer": "Sicily", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdffc6d1cf6db9ac4808cfe", "question": "Where is the world's largest building carved out of a single rock?", "answer": "India", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a072", "question": "What planet did Alf come from?", "answer": "Melmac", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c205", "question": "What year was the US an Olympic Games host for the first time?", "answer": "1904", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe775dbeec85e375820b312", "question": "Where are the Baalbek Roman ruins located?", "answer": "Lebanon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9ae", "question": "In the B&O Railroad, what does B&O stand for?", "answer": "Baltimore and Ohio", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ed", "question": "In The Simpsons, who once attacked Lisa when she was cross-country skiing?", "answer": "Vicious deer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e8cdfe83fe1f2a824bdf", "question": "Which rebellious leader of the Catuvellauni tribe was caught and taken to Rome in AD 50, then pardoned by Emperor Claudius?", "answer": "Caractacus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390d3", "question": "Who is the Greek equivalent of the Roman goddess Diana?", "answer": "Artemis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a25f2f96682715b82711cef", "question": "What is Joseph Priestley credited with discovering?", "answer": "Oxygen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe1332be39efa6330e0fedb", "question": "Which is the driest, non-polar desert on Earth?", "answer": "Atacama Desert", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c003", "question": "What does a philatelist collect?", "answer": "Stamps", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0e0", "question": "During which war did the flag flying above Fort McHenry inspire Francis Scott Key's \"The Star-Spangled Banner\"?", "answer": "War of 1812", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffa3f62c73aa70ea0b70aff", "question": "Pennsylvania has what patriotic motto?", "answer": "\"Virtue, Liberty and Independence\"", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af50", "question": "What happened on September 1, 1939 that led to Britain and France declaring war on Germany?", "answer": "Invasion of Poland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bca4", "question": "What is the heating element in Hasbro's Easy-Bake Oven\"?", "answer": "A lightbulb", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc8", "question": "Which country gave us the dish Cullen Skink?", "answer": "Scotland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339380", "question": "In the movie \"Interview with the Vampire\", what gift does Lestat give to Claudia every year?", "answer": "A doll", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b7ab8e46490a8cc1a6e528e", "question": "In \"The Adventures of Pinocchio\", who did Pinocchio accidentally kill?", "answer": "The Talking Cricket", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015deebfe83fe1f2a824b74", "question": "What countries were involved in the Wars of the Three Kingdoms?", "answer": "England, Ireland, and Scotland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a5", "question": "What is the name of Doc Brown's very clever dog in the \"Back to the Future\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Einstein", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a265", "question": "Who established Paisley Park as his own record label?", "answer": "Prince", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae930a574a5ce6b56b8234", "question": "What was Hebe the goddess of?", "answer": "Youth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7e7", "question": "What \"imaginary\" number is defined as the square root of -1?", "answer": "i", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd667e3a5bfecdd737e086d", "question": "How old did the oldest recorded person live to be?", "answer": "122-years-old", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad7eba2b24f84e0b9f9ffdf", "question": "What town's name means \"House of Bread\" in Hebrew?", "answer": "Bethlehem", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5eb735e75e259d786908732a", "question": "What two men are considered the most notable two-time recepients of Congressional Medals of Honor?", "answer": "Smedley Butler and Dan Daly", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339600", "question": "What movie based on a 1960's TV show was about a family's intergalactic journey through space?", "answer": "Lost in Space", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ed", "question": "What is the chemical symbol for iron?", "answer": "Fe", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339473", "question": "What is the name of the last human city in the movie \"The Matrix\"?", "answer": "Zion", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bf5", "question": "What river is the setting for the novel \"The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn\"?", "answer": "Mississippi River", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6a1", "question": "What is the largest of the islands off the southern coast of Cape Cod?", "answer": "Martha's Vineyard", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133910f", "question": "In which Tennessee Williams' play do you encounter the character \"Big Daddy\"?", "answer": "Cat on a Hot Tin Roof", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1b4", "question": "Anthony Robert McMillan is more famous as who?", "answer": "Robbie Coltrane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae6a", "question": "What age of exploration began on October 4, 1957?", "answer": "The Space Age", "category": "history"}, {"id": "592eae17f83302ff91e46483", "question": "Which creature was the Egyptian God Horus identified with?", "answer": "Falcon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd91", "question": "What Japanese word for \"wave person\" refers to a masterless samurai?", "answer": "Ronin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2d0", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"The Swamp Fox\"?", "answer": "Francis Marion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c79", "question": "What animal is Indiana Jones afraid of?", "answer": "Snakes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e971c7ccba3ffe45786f9", "question": "Melissophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Bees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bdd", "question": "What popular artist co-wrote \"Justify My Love\" with Madonna?", "answer": "Lenny Kravitz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b39e", "question": "Who invented the cash register in 1879?", "answer": "James Ritty", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe1ecbc145fb29466707388", "question": "Where did fondue originate?", "answer": "Switzerland", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a232", "question": "What instrument is jazz musician Charlie Mingus mostly associated with?", "answer": "Double Bass", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6007815fbd51d85e222ab64b", "question": "What art movement employs aspects of mass culture, such as advertising, comic books and mundane cultural objects?", "answer": "Seeking to elevate popular culture to the level of fine art,\u00a0Pop artists\u00a0celebrated commonplace objects and everyday people.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3e7", "question": "Which African nation gained its independence on July 9, 2011?", "answer": "South Sudan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afe3", "question": "During what war did Nathan Hale become a national hero?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a0", "question": "What 1989 Billy Joel hit was included in Junior Scholastic magazine as an educational aid?", "answer": "We Didn't Start the Fire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b647", "question": "What brand was famous for its Little Liver Pills?", "answer": "Carter's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdd7", "question": "What kind of cheese is most commonly sold in the US as processed \"string cheese\"?", "answer": "Mozzarella", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8b28501dd7bf43be5e79f", "question": "What does your moon sign represent?", "answer": "Your subconscious and emotions", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b82a", "question": "How many instruments accompany someone singing \"a cappella\"?", "answer": "None", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fecccbdec223966ae8f88a4", "question": "In what movie did Benedict Cumberbatch wear dentures that were an exact replica of Alan Turing's 60-year old set of false teeth?", "answer": "\"The Imitation Game\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a40a", "question": "In which US state would you find the zip code 12345?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9ee", "question": "What event occurs at Walthamstow Stadium?", "answer": "Greyhound Racing", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c793", "question": "What part of the cheetah does not have any spots?", "answer": "The belly", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec88b4ec223966ae8f8822", "question": "The peripheral device that could be used to connect two Gameboys was called what?", "answer": "Game Link Cable", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5f95af9f55722f97b22684d9", "question": "In the \"Harry Potter\" universe, what does the \"Imperius\" Curse do?", "answer": "Controls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7a49ff048f679a45abea", "question": "What part of the brain is responsible for vision?", "answer": "Occipital", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fde51e6c6c6b019850c9a92", "question": "In what nation were the Dead Sea Scrolls found?", "answer": "Jordan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b35", "question": "In 1976, who was the first woman to become a national network news co-anchor?", "answer": "Barbara Walters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8b5", "question": "Proteus orbits what planet of the solar system?", "answer": "Neptune", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b054", "question": "Who participated on the side of the Earp Brothers in the shootout at the OK Corral in 1881?", "answer": "\"Doc\" Holliday", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8af", "question": "St. Patrick's Day is celebrated on what day in March?", "answer": "17th", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e80464de59ea584496fea4", "question": "What are the names of the two adult Dalmatians in the novel \"The Hundred and One Dalmatians\"?", "answer": "Pongo and Missis", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9a2", "question": "Who wrote the book \"A Brief History of Time'' In 1988?\u00a0", "answer": "Stephen Hawking\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015deadfe83fe1f2a824b70", "question": "What was a claw-like weapon from India designed to fit over the knuckles?", "answer": "Bagh naka", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a920", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Eustis?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe9f6b4ff048f679a45aadd", "question": "What did Albert Einstein win the Nobel Prize for in 1921?", "answer": "For his discovery of the law of the photoelectric effect", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcea", "question": "What two things need to be combined to form an \"interrobang\"?", "answer": "A question mark and an exclamation point", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c452", "question": "What are there 270 of in the average human baby but only 206 in an adult?", "answer": "Bones", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b9", "question": "What was Peter Gunn's girlfriend's name?", "answer": "Edie Hart", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab1b3ef4fda37788a9a1dc5", "question": "Where is the Salvador Dali museum located?", "answer": "St. Petersburg, Florida", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c91c", "question": "This protein makes the blood red in color?", "answer": "Hemoglobin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9f6", "question": "What Sponge cake is baked in the form of a female digit?", "answer": "Lady Fingers", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a60", "question": "In the Beatles song, who shot Rocky Racoon?", "answer": "Dan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5f306ce05a3942286e3f", "question": "Who died tragically young outside L.A.'s Viper Room club?", "answer": "River Phoenix", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae3d", "question": "What slogan did Nancy Reagan create for her drug awareness campaign?", "answer": "Just Say No", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65c541f3c0ead6880d612", "question": "What was the most important celestial object for the Aztecs?", "answer": "The sun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1a5", "question": "What car lost 96 percent of its sales in the four years after the publication of Ralph Nader's \"Unsafe at Any Speed\"?", "answer": "Chevrolet Corvair", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b64e", "question": "What media personality was once a speechwriter for Richard Nixon?", "answer": "Ben Stein", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4f0", "question": "What US States end with the letter N?", "answer": "Michigan, Washington, Oregon and Wisconsin", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6014c4b5fbde8045e48466a0", "question": "What does the African dung beetle use to navigate at night?", "answer": "The Milky Way -- The only animal known to navigate using the Milky Way, they can move objects that are 50 times their weight.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae3b", "question": "What did \"abolitionists\" oppose?", "answer": "Slavery", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff516f0ff04d658268c92f7", "question": "Egyptian workers were often paid with a ration of what?", "answer": "Beer (It was so beloved in Ancient Egypt that it was an accepted form of currency.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdc0", "question": "What is traditionally the main fruit ingredient in a tarte tatin?", "answer": "Apples", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd69fa76c0f9723ab15cb2d", "question": "What was Martin Luther King, Jr.'s birth name?", "answer": "Michael", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b8d7712b42d4a3561a9f0d", "question": "What fast food businessman does Michael Keaton portray in the 2016 film \u201cThe Founder\u201d?", "answer": "Ray Kroc", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a797", "question": "Havana is located on which side of Cuba?", "answer": "The west", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe000791cf6db9ac4808d12", "question": "What are the Philippines named after?", "answer": "Spain's King Philip II", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef92cd6ce05a3942286e87", "question": "Which famous actor was orginally offered the role of Tommy Williams in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Brad Pitt", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fede4d06ce05a3942286de2", "question": "On which real-life serial killer was the killer in the film \"Scream\" based?", "answer": "Danny Rolling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd81fc7d0de9af39e9d4699", "question": "What virtue do the red stripes on the American flag stand for?", "answer": "Valor", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adfe", "question": "Which city hosted the Olympic Games in 2000?", "answer": "Sydney", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339225", "question": "Who plays the role of Craig the puppeteer's wife in \"Being John Malkovich\"?", "answer": "Cameron Diaz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4c9", "question": "What part of New York was called \"broken land\" by the Dutch?", "answer": "Brooklyn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5e2", "question": "What name is given to the fruit of an oak tree?", "answer": "An acorn", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a131", "question": "Who created the TV show \"Jeeves and Wooster\"?", "answer": "Clive Exton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b580", "question": "What year was the first iPhone released?", "answer": "2007", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338de0", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"safari\"?", "answer": "Arabic", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7c9", "question": "What year did Apple introduce its first retail store?", "answer": "2001", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9cb", "question": "What kind of animal is a Lurcher?", "answer": "Dog", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a4d", "question": "Natty Bumppo was the creation of which author?", "answer": "James Fenimore Cooper", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b84d", "question": "What is the Hebrew word for peace, used as both a greeting and a farewell?", "answer": "Shalom", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c893", "question": "What does the Schmidt index measure?", "answer": "Pain of insect stings", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c09", "question": "What year was Anna Nicole Smith selected as a Playboy Playmate of the Year?", "answer": "1993", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd8c", "question": "What ingredient appears alongside potatoes in the Indian dish aloo gobi?", "answer": "Cauliflower", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339810", "question": "What was rapper Rick Ross' occupation prior to becoming a hip hop artist?", "answer": "Correctional officer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe938766bd93ce3a4e5f685", "question": "Who won a Nobel Prize in Chemistry in 2009 for studies of the structure and function of the ribosome?", "answer": "Ada E. Yonath", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ecaec9e790ded87bb38fd90", "question": "In the 1984 film, \"Purple Rain\", who did The Kid tell to purify herself in the waters of Lake Minnetonka?", "answer": "Apollonia", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f28", "question": "Who wrote \"The Pilgrim's Progress\" while in prison?", "answer": "John Bunyan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a155", "question": "Who married actress Julia Roberts in 1993?", "answer": "Lyle Lovett", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ff", "question": "What do the bar code letters UPC stand for?", "answer": "Universal Product Code", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aff4", "question": "John F. Kennedy was a member of which political party?", "answer": "Democratic Party", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8b7", "question": "In what city would you find Rock Creek Park?", "answer": "Washington, D.C.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be14", "question": "What does a DNR order at a hospital stand for?", "answer": "Do Not Resuscitate", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5c77cf6424f0f7a362efd54d", "question": "In \"The Legend of Zelda: Ocarina of Time\", how many races are there?", "answer": "6", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b990", "question": "Which NBA team plays its home games at the Barclays Centre?", "answer": "Brooklyn Nets", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb69765dad637d903c8848", "question": "In which U.S. state can you find a river nicknamed the \"River of No Return\"?", "answer": "Idaho", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd668bba5bfecdd737e0872", "question": "Which religion has the most gods?", "answer": "Hinduism", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d0342596a59cbdfbd378", "question": "Who said, \"Nature has given us two ears, two eyes, and but one tongue-to the end that we should hear and see more than we speak\"?", "answer": "Socrates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395c3", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Krusty Gets Busted\", according to Bart, what do all good-hearted people have?", "answer": "Small feet", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2b6", "question": "Which of Henry VIII's wives was the mother of Queen Elizabeth I?", "answer": "Anne Boleyn", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff3cfe34f032c0db195b493", "question": "What monarch of the Zulu Kingdom was assassinated by his half brothers Dingane and Mhlangana?", "answer": "Shaka kaSenzangakhona, also known as Shaka Zulu", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e08", "question": "What does Doctor Who's vast spacecraft, the TARDIS, look like from the outside?", "answer": "A police box", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3c3", "question": "What is the most popular spirit produced in Jamaica?", "answer": "Rum", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe8f8ed01dd7bf43be5e849", "question": "What is the largest three-digit prime number?", "answer": "997", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ff0b25fe662d71a53650fd7", "question": "Botticelli's \"Birth of Venus\" features a goddess floating in the ocean on what?", "answer": "Seashell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b7abd426490a8cc1a6e529e", "question": "What is the capital city of England", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a67d", "question": "Wisconsin has a shoreline along which two Great Lakes?", "answer": "Superior and Michigan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a01f", "question": "Which of the two leads of 1995's movie \"Friday\" didn't appear in either of the sequels?", "answer": "Chris Tucker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e865fe83fe1f2a824bdc", "question": "The Chinese Exclusion Act was signed into law by which US president in 1882?", "answer": "Chester A Arthur", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b070", "question": "Who the first American World Chess Champion?", "answer": "Bobby Fisher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d1f", "question": "Helen Keller was related to what former Confederate general?", "answer": "Robert E. Lee", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af46", "question": "Who was the famous teacher of Socrates?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0c5", "question": "In 1996 and 2000, who was the presidential nominee from the Green Party?", "answer": "Ralph Nader", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a7f720565ad31a57c7f1", "question": "What President\u2019s fondness for pork rinds made sales of the snack boom?", "answer": "George H. W. Bush", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339250", "question": "What Stanley Kubrick movie was hyped: \"In Vietnam the wind doesn't blow, it sucks\"?", "answer": "Full Metal Jacket", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae69", "question": "What did Ronald Reagan disclose he was suffering from in 1994?", "answer": "Alzheimer's Disease", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd54", "question": "The Obie Award is an award given in what field?", "answer": "Off-Broadway theater", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe6a91420565ad31a57c7fc", "question": "What Dallas nightclub did Oswald murderer Jack Ruby own?", "answer": "The Carousel Club", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a04", "question": "Whose \"Coffee Cantata\" concerns a girl whose father demands she loses her addiction to coffee before marriage?", "answer": "Johann Sebastian Bach's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe939526bd93ce3a4e5f68c", "question": "What plant do scientists use to clean up radioactive waste?", "answer": "Sunflowers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b199", "question": "What Germany city hosted the 1972 Olympic games?", "answer": "Munich", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c952", "question": "The angel shark is commonly referred to by what other name?", "answer": "Monkfish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b6f6e662d71a53651011", "question": "Moved by a desire to help people, Vincent van Gogh left art to become what?", "answer": "A priest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c68a", "question": "Ranger VII was the first US spacecraft to send back pictures of what?", "answer": "The moon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5febd9b57e83c707845b217c", "question": "In 2016, Giants' wide receiver Odell Beckham, Jr. appeared on which television series?", "answer": "Beckham appeared as himself on a 2016 episode of the series \"Code Black\" entitled \"Hail Mary\".", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bda1", "question": "What are the \"ten\" referred to when a surfer \"hangs ten\" on a wave?", "answer": "His ten toes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b54a", "question": "What is the highest hand in straight Poker?", "answer": "A royal flush", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b384", "question": "Mary Read and Anne Bonny had what job in common?", "answer": "Pirates", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a868", "question": "Which countries share land borders with Spain?", "answer": "France, Portugal and Andorra", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a725", "question": "Mount Whitney is the highest peak in which mountain range?", "answer": "Sierra Nevada Range", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fe9", "question": "Who directed his own father to Oscar gold in \"The Treasure of the Sierra Nevada\"?", "answer": "John Huston", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f01", "question": "Whose \"Adagio for Strings\" is best known as the theme from the movie \"Platoon\"?", "answer": "Samuel Barber's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f16a39f7c52aae91cc07d9", "question": "Who is the main character is Shakespeare's \"The Tempest\"?", "answer": "Prospero", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59008f8bcf842fa4c4ba96bd", "question": "Who is the Roman Patron Saint of hangovers?", "answer": "Saint Bibiana", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba80", "question": "What was the original name of \"TV Guide\"?", "answer": "TV Digest", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b67", "question": "What is Dr. Watson's first name?", "answer": "John", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab88", "question": "Phnom Penh is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Cambodia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8a0", "question": "How many minutes does it take to complete a 12 round boxing match?", "answer": "47 minutes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5e1", "question": "What type of a drum has vibrating wires across its bottom?", "answer": "Snare drum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338976", "question": "What is replaced in the hand of William Shakespeare's graveside memorial bust each year on the anniversary of his death?", "answer": "Quill", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59029fe7cad1ec93f27df765", "question": "What country does the cappuccino originate from?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6c0", "question": "From 1948 to 1950, the Fender Telecaster was known by what alternate name?", "answer": "Broadcaster", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e3f46a5cb9e8bda6821368", "question": "What year did Charles Perrault publish his version of the folk tale \"Cinderella\"?", "answer": "1697", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5909cd39bb53d1af658864e7", "question": "What gives traditional eggnog its frothy texture?", "answer": "Whipped eggs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a55c", "question": "What city is nicknamed the \"Big Apple\"?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca34", "question": "What geological period followed the Jurassic?", "answer": "Cretaceous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe7bd0c877e98cb97778952", "question": "What river runs through Baghdad?", "answer": "Tigris", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ddf", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"alcohol\"?", "answer": "Arabic", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133971c", "question": "In \"The Addams Family\", what does Morticia do that always excites Gomez?", "answer": "Speaks French", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c523877e98cb977789ab", "question": "Which island was once named the \"Island of the Pelicans\"?", "answer": "Alcatraz Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd2d3172596a59cbdfbd397", "question": "What river flows into the world's largest waterfall?", "answer": "Zambezi River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfb7", "question": "Which building material gets its name from Arabic for \"brick\"?", "answer": "Adobe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c211", "question": "What year were the first Winter Olympic Games held?", "answer": "1924", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e72cbb2d0874f1a5e2d1c22", "question": "How many years is a \"Copyright Protection\" granted in the United States to an author after their death?", "answer": "70 years", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe735abeec85e375820b24f", "question": "Who said, \"If you have ten thousand regulations you destroy all respect for the law.\"?", "answer": "Winston Churchill", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fbc", "question": "The critical clue in what movie turns out to be a Japanese gardener complaining that salt water is \"bad for glass\"?", "answer": "Chinatown", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc4c", "question": "Who is credited with inventing Coca-Cola?", "answer": "John Pemberton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391c2", "question": "What is Marilyn Monroe's real name?", "answer": "Norma Jeane Mortenson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cc1", "question": "What band's Greatest Hits album set a US record by going 29 times platinum?", "answer": "Eagles'", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecccdaec223966ae8f88a6", "question": "What country does \"The Hunger Games\" take place in?", "answer": "Panem", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339258", "question": "Who performed the song \"The Power of Love\" with his band in the movie \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "Huey Lewis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394c7", "question": "What planet was Mork from in the TV show \"Mork & Mindy\"?", "answer": "Ork", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "590722e33745b36be7303a03", "question": "What popular Christmas song did Eartha Kitt record in 1953?", "answer": "Santa Baby", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded1b3ea2747c8aff16d35", "question": "What year was the word \"motel\" first used?", "answer": "1925", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4c6f49076251badbead4", "question": "Who once owned the land on which Arlington National Cemetery is situated?", "answer": "Confederate General Robert E. Lee", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4ec4a06d333868d34d763", "question": "What was the term for the official policy of racial segregation in South Africa until 1994?", "answer": "Apartheid", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601b4bc649076251badbeac8", "question": "What was U.S. President Woodrow Wilson's reelection campaign slogan in 1916?", "answer": "\"He Kept Us Out of War\" -- Despite the slogan, he asked Congress to declare war in 1917.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a47c", "question": "In which city is the European Court of Justice?", "answer": "Luxembourg", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fefc45d6ce05a3942286f31", "question": "The pop band, The Bangles, would like for their fans to walk like what?", "answer": "An Egyptian", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b95b", "question": "What is heartsease?", "answer": "A flower", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339015", "question": "What writing system originated in Sumer around 3,000 BCE?", "answer": "Cuneiform", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1f7", "question": "Who starred in the 1951 film \"Show Boat\" as Julie?\u00a0", "answer": "Ava Gardner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe655e3ae7e414034b5aebd", "question": "What Greek figure was famously forced to complete 12 Labors?", "answer": "Hercules", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ce9", "question": "Tuesday Weld played Thalia Menninger on what TV show?", "answer": "The Many Loves of Dobie Gillis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e6", "question": "What two states share a border with Florida?", "answer": "Alabama and Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd66d78a5bfecdd737e08a1", "question": "Who reached 1 million Instagram followers the fastest?", "answer": "Jennifer Aniston", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59067f54ff9c0647b50a8083", "question": "In October of 2016, just 2 months after its initial release, what product did Samsung stop manufacturing and selling?", "answer": "Galaxy Note 7", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6a95d20565ad31a57c802", "question": "During \"Operation Torch,\" who were the Alies' primary adversaries?", "answer": "The Vichy French", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a93e", "question": "The island in the middle of Victoria Falls is named for what famous man?", "answer": "David Livingstone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4b6c206d333868d34d6f4", "question": "What did France give to Vassar College at the end of World War I?", "answer": "A tank", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a5b", "question": "What American poet wrote: \"The fog comes on little cat feet\"?", "answer": "Carl Sandburg", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d118174fea7fe947a22281", "question": "What metal has the chemical symbol Pb?", "answer": "Lead", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e6a", "question": "What does Miss Havisham constantly wear in Dickens' \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Her wedding dress", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "591c3709815febcc896f926c", "question": "What city provided the setting for the 1970's TV show \"One Day at a Time\"?", "answer": "Indianapolis", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5cb70db4f96e155acab35d34", "question": "What is the national animal of Scotland?", "answer": "Unicorn", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "600f7209a9e54d890926f6e9", "question": "What is the biggest desert in Australia?", "answer": "Great Victoria Desert -- Located in Western and South Australia, it is home to several nature reserves and a national park.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba90", "question": "In what city did Major League Baseball\u2019s Braves franchise first begin?", "answer": "Boston", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600782aebd51d85e222ab659", "question": "Who claimed he could \"drive away the devil with a fart\"?", "answer": "Martin Luther", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbeb", "question": "What year saw Jean Paul Gaultier's first individual collection for women?", "answer": "1976", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a844", "question": "What UK city is served by John Lennon Airport?", "answer": "Liverpool", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5bb356992627b8fe95581bdf", "question": "What is the name of the tallest flagpole in the world?", "answer": "The Jeddah Flagpole", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338916", "question": "What fairy tale character has two ugly stepsister?", "answer": "Cinderella", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b51e", "question": "What gives Tonic Water its flavour?", "answer": "Quinine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a202", "question": "Diane Belmont was the stage name of which famous actress?", "answer": "Lucille Ball", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b585", "question": "What is the Canadian dollar coin called?", "answer": "Loonie", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5ca", "question": "Who created the operating system \"Linux\"?", "answer": "Linus Torvalds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af72", "question": "The US boycotted the 1980 Olympics to protest what Soviet action?", "answer": "Soviet invasion of Afghanistan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb2e", "question": "In 1997, who became the first racecar driver to be featured on the front of a Wheaties box?", "answer": "Dale Earnhardt", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3fe", "question": "The surface of the dwarf planet Pluto is made largely of what type of frozen gas?", "answer": "Methane", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba64", "question": "Which US city is home to the Second City Comedy Troupe?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399a5", "question": "What Hanna-Barbera cartoon characters were patterned after Ed Norton from the TV series \"The Honeymooners\"?", "answer": "Yogi Bear and Barney Rubble", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339081", "question": "Who wrote \"Born Free\", \"Living Free\" and \"Forever Free\"?", "answer": "Joy Adamson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ac", "question": "Julia Roberts and Hugh Grant were paired in what romantic comedy?", "answer": "Notting Hill", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf8e", "question": "What US state includes the telephone area code 608?", "answer": "Wisconsin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b02", "question": "Which character killed Elizabeth Lavenza?", "answer": "Frankestein's monster", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c343", "question": "What is the sound a camel makes called?", "answer": "Nuzzing", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb8a", "question": "What type of stuffed animal does an arctophile collect?", "answer": "Teddy bears", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe525631bf59ab7d2e380f3", "question": "Which animal is pictured on the standard Canadian $2 coin?", "answer": "Polar bear", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c385", "question": "In medical terminology, the \"voice box\" is known as what?", "answer": "Larynx", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bf6c", "question": "What's the term for a bet before cards are dealt?", "answer": "Ante", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8fe", "question": "How far is the free throw line from the backboard in basketball?", "answer": "15 feet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5e910598d7247dfc0fa00313", "question": "What year was the element Berkelium discovered?", "answer": "1949", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe8b8b701dd7bf43be5e7ed", "question": "A group of lizards is called what?", "answer": "A lounge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfc9", "question": "Nudophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Nudity", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b25c", "question": "Which amendment to the US Constitution deals with women's suffrage?", "answer": "Nineteenth", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a852", "question": "Approximately, how many feet above the sea level is Machi Picchu located at?", "answer": "8,000", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398da", "question": "What TV series starred trail hands Gil Favor and Rowdy Yates?", "answer": "Rawhide", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ae4", "question": "Which artist is famous for his statue The Thinker?", "answer": "Auguste Rodin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a3c8319039f3d7859290ff7", "question": "In the TV Show \"Bonanza\", what was Ben Cartwright\u2019s profession prior to moving to Nevada and buying the Ponderosa?", "answer": "Ship\u2019s chandler", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b9c0", "question": "Which Nintendo character made the line \"Do a barrel roll!\" famous?", "answer": "Peppy", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cfa", "question": "In which movie did Christina Ricci portray a witch?", "answer": "Sleepy Hollow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd2d6f82596a59cbdfbd3b0", "question": "Who invented the lint roller?", "answer": "Nicholas McKay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "591c349c815febcc896f9253", "question": "On which of the Canary Island would you find the holiday destination of Corralejo?", "answer": "Fuerteventura", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c829", "question": "What is the liquid component of blood called?", "answer": "Plasma", "category": "science"}]